Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit, I am the founder
of Family First Financial Services, I am an MBA Finance and have been working in the corporate sector for 14 years
and today on 22 January 2025, on the completion of one year of Ram Lalla's Pran Pratishtha,
ICS Protense Life Insurance launched a new guaranteed product named
Gift Select where you can take early income, you can take income as soon as the policy is issued, you
can take income after one year of the policy, you can take income after 5 years, if you
want to take income after 15 years, you can take it, you can take income for up to 30 years, you will get income
immediately after the policy is issued, you can also take level income
and if you want to take income in increasing mode at the compounding rate of 5% every year, you
can take it, if you want to get the entire money back on maturity, you can take it, if you want to get double the money back on maturity,
you can take it, here you
can take this income in monthly mode, you can take it If you want to take it in annual mode, you can take it.
I will also tell you in detail in this video how to reinvest and utilize this plan.
Watch this video completely and if you like the video, then
definitely subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS. Definitely like, share and subscribe where you
will get more than 300 videos which will help you in your financial planning. By the way, this channel is
India's largest insurance pay.
Let's understand all these benefits step by step. Now how does the early income option work?
Suppose a 35-year-old person is taking a deferred period of one year and
is taking the option of income in advance, that is, if he has purchased the policy on January 3, 2025,
then from January 3, 2026, he will start getting an income of Rs 34,500
for the next 29 years because he has taken one year paid in deferred plus the
entire money paid 100%, he has taken the option of return premium, so the entire amount
paid is 100%. They will get back ₹ lakhs. The thing to understand here is that the period in def
is one year, the income is in advance, so after 1 year but the income is in advance, so
immediately in January 2026, they are getting income, but the income is not in advance and
if the def period was one year, then the income would have started coming from January 2027, but it
would not be 34500, it would be 37 to 8000, how much would it be? I
will explain you in details in the benefit illustration further. Now let's understand step by step all the options and
features with the benefit illustration. First of all, let's understand
that there is a person whose name is Anil Rajput and he is 35 years old and he
is selecting the option of early income. Here you
will see where he is paying premium for 12 years and
selecting a policy term of 30 years and paying premium of ₹ lakhs annually, the customer is 35 years old,
the name of the plan is IIC Proof Gift Select, which is a non-profit plan. It is a participating non-linked
plan, that is, a 100% guaranteed plan. In this plan, in the first year, you
will be charged GST on 4.5% and in the remaining years, you will be charged GST of 21%. In the plan, the option of
level income is taken where the guaranteed income will start from the second year,
but here you have selected to take the income in advance, that is,
if you purchase the policy in January 2025, then the income will start coming from January 2026,
which will be written in this bone of your policy. You see here that if you
have purchased the policy in January 2025, then you will start getting income from January 2026 itself.
How much income is coming? 8831. This is the option of income in advance.
If you do not select this option of income in advance, then your income
will be a little more here. I will tell you a little about that later. Plus,
let us know about ICICI that ICICI has so far purchased 99.84 crore policies. It has been sold in which
the company has paid benefits like bonus etc. worth Rs. 2.87 crore. This
is a company worth Rs. 3 lakh crore. You will also get quick claim settlement, race tax benefits etc. in this plan.
So here how much income will you get in advance?
8831. So you will get this income for 29 years because you have taken a deferment feed for one year.
So the total income will be Rs. 23,4499 plus the premiums you have paid
Rs. 100 lakh will be refunded to you. So you will see this in the table where
in the maturity column, you will get back your paid Rs. 24 lakh as 100% return of premium.
Talking about death benefit, the death benefit
will be the highest of column number six and nine. What is the minimum death benefit in column number six?
What is the special surrender value in column number nine? The higher of these two will
be your death benefit. The surrender value is generated in this policy from the first year itself.
If you have taken the policy in annual mode or in monthly mode also, then after paying full 12 premiums,
after 12 premiums in monthly mode and after one premium in annual mode,
your surrender value is generated against which you can take loan till the age of 80 and
whenever death occurs, the higher of these, that benefit and special surrender value, its
higher benefit will be given to you as a nominee. If you
do not select the option of advance in early income, suppose the customer has selected income and
is getting income from the second year, but this time he is selecting the option of arrears and not taking the advance,
what does it mean, the income will not come in 2026, when will it come, the income will come in 2027, but
your income has increased from 7000 to 87,860, here you will start getting income, if you
look here, you are seeing 87,000 from the second year, but you must always check the date,
from which date you are getting the income Income is starting to come and at the end the maturity will
remain the same. So if you want to take the income in advance, that is, you
want to take it at the beginning of the year, you want to take it at the end of this year, you can see that here.
Now let's see the second option, income on insurance. Suppose you are a 35-year-old person,
paying ₹ lakh premium, paying for 10 years, taking a policy term of 30 years,
taking deferred zero, taking income in advance, then this time he
will get an income of ₹ 31900 instead of ₹ 34500, but that income
will come immediately. Suppose you purchase in January 2025, then you will get the income in January 2025 itself.
Now let's see the next option, where you
have selected level income, but this time you have not taken the deferment of one year.
You want income from the first year, that is, the time when you purchased the policy, that is,
suppose you purchased the policy in January 2025. If it is in January 2025, this year, this
month, that is, if you purchase in February 2025, then you
will start getting income in February 2025 itself because this time you are not waiting for one year, so you
will get an income of ₹ 4851 and you
will also get match benefit. As return of premium, I have kept 100%, you
can also keep 200 or 150 if you want, then the income will keep increasing and decreasing accordingly. Now here you
will see that I have selected the option of advance, this time I
have not kept a waiting period of one year, so here you are getting total income of 22 4553 plus return of premium.
This time the income, because there is no waiting period of one year, will come for 30 years and not 29
years, so this ₹ 4000 is coming to you in annual mode. If you
want to take it in monthly mode also, then you can also select the option of monthly mode.
And here you Maturity will be seen, if we talk about instant cash cashback,
then suppose a 35-year-old person pays Rs 1 lakh for 10 years,
takes a policy term of 30 years, takes a deferment period of one year and takes income in advance,
that is, from January 2026, he will start getting income for the next 29 years, then there
will also be return of premium, in this he will start getting income of Rs 00600, but earlier when
you purchased the policy, suppose in January 2025 you purchased the policy and
paid a premium of one lakh and you selected cashback at 50, then as soon as the policy is issued,
you will get Rs 50000 immediately and from next year you will get income of Rs 00600 for 29 years
and the deposited Rs 10 lakh will also be available to you tax free on maturity, taking instant income,
when you take instant income, you will have to take it in year two here, guaranteed income which
will not be required for two years in the start year and here
you can take the advance You are also selecting the option that means you get the income in advance that means
it will start from next year but you will get instant income, I
have taken instant income here, 50 per 50 for your annual premium, so here you see as soon as you
purchase the policy, the policy will be issued, immediately you will get Rs 1 lakh in your account and then
you will get an income of 7974 every year from January 2026 and
on maturity of the policy you will get back ₹ 1 lakh, the option of level income
is simple that like this income of ₹ 4000 is coming every year, neither it is decreasing nor increasing,
this is called level income, let's talk about increasing income, this
is happening for the first time in the insurance industry where the income which
is coming in an increasing order is coming in increasing mode, it is coming at the compounding rate, rest
of the company has plans where the option of increasing is given, it
increases at the simple interest rate, but in this plan The compounding rate will increase
the income from your money through interest. For example, a 35-year-old person
pays a premium of Rs 1 lakh and takes income in advance for a deposition period of one year.
If you are taking this option then here you will get an income of 200000 from the first year but it will increase
to 74000 and you will also get the benefit of return of premium. Here
I have selected the option of increasing income. You
will start getting income from the second year and in the increasing mode, it will increase at the rate of 5% and that too
at the compounding rate. This is the first time in the industry where you
get guaranteed income at the compounding rate. All the other plans of the company
grow at the simple interest rate. So here how much income will you get in the first year?
46000 846 and the last income you will start getting is 183 644.
Here, whether you have taken the option of instant cashback or not, the total income you are getting
is 2919 594 and the rest of the money deposited
will also be matched back. For how many years will the total income come? For 29 years, it is 46000 in the first year
and then it is 49. Then there is 51000, then there is 54000, in this way it goes in increasing order, so
if you think that I do not need money right now, I
need a bigger income in the future, even as a pension, if you
want to utilize it, you can do that, then you will get income in increasing order and
you can withdraw the entire ₹ lakh paid, this return of premium, if you
want to keep it at 100%, 150, 200, you can keep
it, in this plan you are given many different options of return of premium, you
can also withdraw 100% of the money paid, you can take return of premium at 150 also,
if you want to take it at 200 also, you can take it, suppose you
are paying a premium of ₹ lakh for 10 years, then you will pay ₹ lakh, then after 20, 30 years, if you want 20 lakhs
at once, then also you can take it because you will get that 200 but what will happen with this
that The income you are getting every year will reduce a little bit. Here
I have taken the level income option in which you need income from the first year and that means
you should start getting income from 2026. Sorry, here the income option you
selected was to purchase in January 2025 and you need income in the same month in which you purchased in January 2025.
I have selected the option of advance
where you are getting an income of 50-710 rupees. But this time you have taken the
option of return of premium at 200 rupees. That means
the percentage of the 24 lakhs you paid in 12 years becomes 48 lakhs. You will get 8 lakhs on maturity. You think
that this is the income I don't need much 70-800-800,000. I have enough 50,000 rupees. But when
after 30 years I need a premium for children's education or marriage or for setting up my own business for
some other purpose, then I will get 8 lakhs. If you need a big amount then you
can select the option in this way here.
An excellent option has been given in this plan for the deferment period which
can start from 1 year and can last till the policy term minus one year. It means if you
have taken a policy term of 30 years, you can wait for one year and take income from the next year as well. If the policy term
is 30 - 1, then even after 29 years, if you want to take income, that is if you
want to take income only once, in simple language, if you want to take the sum of money at once, you can take it.
You can utilize it in many ways, for example, suppose you
have taken deferment for 10 years, then you will get income for 20 years but this time the amount will increase.
Suppose you have selected income for 4 years, suppose you have taken deferment
for 25-26 years, then you will get income for four to five years, which
will be a big income. So if you spend money on children's education, their marriage or If you want to use it to set up your own
business, you can do that. There is another good
option of deferment pad, which is to select the policy term minus or
you can use it as a lump sum policy. For example, there
is an income option, here you have the income option, but here you will see that
you are not getting any income, you will directly
get a guaranteed income of Rs. 74 lakh 4540 and you will get Rs. 1 lakh on maturity,
your income increases to around Rs. 1 crore, where you
invest Rs. 2 lakh for 12 years, then you are getting a tax free guaranteed income of around Rs. 1 crore, because this
time what you have done is that you have purchased the income term for one year and not for 29 years,
that means you have kept all the other deferred benefits, so in this way, if you
want to take a single premium for 25 years or
even for 20 years, not for 30 years, you can take it. But all this has to be selected
at the time of inception while buying the policy. Let us understand with an example that there is a customer
Those who are not selecting a 30-year policy term this time
are selecting 25 years only. Suppose they have a child who is a year or two old and they think that when he
turns 20, here I have taken as an example that they
need income from 22 years onwards and for how many years they need income, only for 4 years so that they
keep getting Rs. 9000 for higher education, so they got 10 lakhs
for nine years which will be useful for their higher education, plus
the maturity of 10 lakhs and 24 lakhs, you will get a huge amount of around 44-35 lakhs which can be useful for you in marriage,
so in this way also you can utilize it in a systematic way in marriage and education,
so how do you need money at different stages of life, in
increasing order, if you need it at a level, if you need money early, if you need it later, if you need it for fewer years, if you
need it for more years, if you get the entire money in a single year,
that is right, you can choose all the options according to your requirement. You can purchase it by designing it.
If you want to understand the impact of increasing income, then you can see here that a 35-year-old
person is paying 10 years premium and taking a policy term of 30 years and
is also giving the option of cash back at 50% and there is a deferred period of 1 year.
He has selected the option of income in advance. If he takes level income, then he
will get an income of 0608 in level i.e. during 30 years, he
will get an income of 887,632 in 29 years plus he will get return of premium. But if he
takes the increasing option, then in the first year he
will get an income of 7738 but it will increase to 9000, so the overall income
will be 115,456 in front of 8 lakh plus return of premium. So you
can select it according to your requirement, if you need a big income quickly, then
select level income. If you feel that you need income after a few years, then select the income. If so, you
can select the increasing option or you can also take the
flexible return of premium option. Here you can see that suppose
you take 100% return of premium, then you will get an income of something like Rs. 0000 and the overall total benefit
is Rs. 87,000 but if you take return of premium at Rs. 200, then the annual income you
will get will be Rs. 19,000 and not Rs. 18 lakh but the total benefit will be Rs. 1 lakh. How do you say all this?
If you need money later because you
have taken return of premium at Rs. 200, then the income is coming less, that means the opportunity which you
were getting for investment, suppose if you were getting Rs. 0000, you were getting Rs. 11,000 extra income, then you
can invest it somewhere and convert it into returns but if you
are not taking it and are keeping it deposited in the company and later you are taking double the money, then
the company will give you a little more The amount is giving them more interest because they
are accumulative. If you are happy with Rs. 20,000 and
want a bigger amount later, then increase the option of interest. If you want more money quickly,
then you can reduce the RP a little. As per your requirement, you
can modify this plan in a way, whether you need instant cashback or not. What
will be its impact? If you do not take instant cashback, then your income will be around Rs. 000.
If you take cashback up to 25, then you will have an income of Rs. 32,000 and if you take it up to 50, then
the income will be around Rs. 00. So you can also select this according to your requirement
whether you want instant cashback or not or how much percentage you want
. In what way can you utilize this plan in a smart way like a debt fund and
the income that is coming from this, you
can take the benefit of equity by doing SIP in mutual fund, then your portfolio will also be balanced and you will
also get guaranteed income. How will you get it? For example, suppose a 35-year-old person who
pays Rs. 1 lakh premium annually
is selecting a policy term of 30 years for 12 years and he wants to get guaranteed income from the first month and here he
will get income. He chooses it in monthly mode so that he can do SIP every month and then
he will get an income of Rs. 392 per month and Rs. 9704 per year, so the total
income will be around Rs. 59 lakh and that too will be for 30 years and he will get back the full Rs. 6 lakh.
Now if we do SIP for Rs. 16100, Rs. 392 for the next 30 years,
what will be the benefit? Let us see now, let us see in what way, let us assume
that the income that we are getting is Rs. 9674, i.e. Rs. 16000 something, which we
are getting every month, if we do SIP with that, then in what way
will we get the benefit? Let us assume that if you settle for SIP at Rs 12, then you will get returns of Rs 5 lakh.
You paid premium for 12 years, got an income of 9674, reinvested it,
got interest of 12 per cent on it. So, you got interest of 2604.
So, after completion of the whole year, your deposit in the mutual fund was 2
20308. Next year it was 22308 and your 196000 which were reinvested
, total comes to 4112. On that, you got interest of 12 per cent. 5048.
So, at the end of the corpus, my
4675.5 was
reinvested in the mutual fund, then 46 7000 plus the payout that I got next year, 196000. So, my total reinvestment was 6637.58,
on which I earned interest of 9651 as per interest of 12 per cent. So, at the end of the year,
my corpus was 743.409. In the same way, you can invest in different years. Keep looking at
how much corpus you will have by which year. When 30 years are completed,
you will have accumulated a huge corpus of 5 crore 3167 637.
By the way, you are also getting a match here. You are also getting a match of ₹ 1 lakh in ICICI,
so if you add that to it, then you will have earned around 6 crores. Secondly,
you see here that if
I get returns in SIP for 15%, then my corpus will increase from 5 crores to
9 crores 8343 526. In this way, if different
returns are also received, then you can get a good corpus here. So you should
use this plan of ICICI as a dead fund because its rates
will never decrease in the next 30 years. Whereas if you see the rates of FD etc.,
what was it 10 years ago, what is it today, what will it be after 10 years, nobody knows, but
you are getting guaranteed income from there and Here your investment is also being made,
the portfolio is also getting balanced, tax benefits are also being given.
Talking about the eligibility criteria, here
a person from newborn baby to 55 years can purchase this policy where the minimum premium will be Rs. 1 lakh.
The premium payment term can be selected from 7 years, 8 years, 9 years, 10 years, 11 years and 12 years.
The maximum policy term can be of 30 years
. You can take the policy term from deferred payment zero to minus 1 year. Talking about other
benefits and features of this policy, no riders are available in this policy. Surrender benefit:
If you have paid the full premium in the first place, then surrender benefits will be generated for you.
In the policy, you will get up to 80% of the surrender value.
You will get free luck and grace premium for 30 days and you will get a revival period of 5 years. If for some reason
you are unable to pay the premium on time, then you can cancel the policy by paying late fee etc.
You can revive it. Finally, if I surprise this plan, it is an excellent plan
in which your various needs have been kept in mind, whether it is children's education
or marriage, or whether you want to reinvest it, you need early income, you need instant income
after a few years, you need referral income, if you
want less or more return of premium, then a lot of varieties are given in this policy which you
can take according to your need. Now if you want to know that this type of plan which
gives you guaranteed income from the first year itself, is this plan better or is the plan of any other company
better where more income comes, then other companies also have such plans,
but to know which one will give more income, you can consult me
​​on WhatsApp2, compare and buy. If you liked the video, then before leaving,
definitely like and share it, subscribe. If you subscribe, then in future you
will get to see my videos first, which can also be on the plans of other companies
and they will also help you in financial planning.
Thank you so much, Jai Hind.